Guide to the Edna Kenton Correspondence
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Edna Kenton Correspondence,
1903-1954.
Kenton, Edna, 1876-1954.
146 items (1 box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078979
Biographical Note
Author.
Scope and Content
Letters to Kenton from outstanding literary figures such as Theodore Dreiser, Carl Van Vechten, Charles Hanson Towne, George Cram Cook, Henry L. Mencken, Richard Watson Gilder, Witter Bynner. The correspondence is partly personal, and part relates to the Provincetown Players, but chiefly the letters are from editors of various magazines including DELINEATOR and SMART SET, to which Kenton contributed stories.
Arrangement
Material is arranged into one series: Series I: Edna Kenton Correspondence, 1903-1954.
Subjects
Provincetown Players.; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945.; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964.; Towne, Charles Hanson, 1877-1949.; Cook, George Cram, 1873-1924.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Gilder, Richard Watson, 1844-1909.; Bynner, Witter, 1881-1968.; Literature--Periodicals.; Literature publishing.; Women authors.; Smart set.; Delineator.
Acquisition
1954 M-54 Bancroft 15668E Purchase
- Series I: Edna Kenton Correspondence, 1903-1954
  - Altsheler, Joseph, 1907 August 31 (Box 1)
  - Bannon, Henry, 1930 April 18 (Box 1)
  - Barnes, Djuna--An Irish Triangle, A Play in One Act, undated (Box 1)
  - Boyer, Norman, 1910 February 11 (Box 1)
  - Bynner, Witter
    - undated (Box 1)
    - 1910 January 12 (Box 1)
    - 1911 March 6 (Box 1)
    - 1911 April 11 (Box 1)
    - 1911 July 10 (Box 1)
    - 1911 November 24 (Box 1)
    - 1913 June 27 (Box 1)
  - Cook, George Cram, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Dana, Marvin
    - 1903 November 9 (Box 1)
    - 1904 April 7 (Box 1)
  - Dell, Berta Marie Gage (Mrs. Floyd), undated (Box 1)
  - Dell, Floyd, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Dreiser, Theodore
    - undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1906 September 25 (Box 1)
    - 1906 November 7 (Box 1)
    - 1907 March 27 (Box 1)
    - 1907 June 18 (Box 1)
    - 1907 July 2 (Box 1)
    - 1907 July 18 (Box 1)
    - 1907 August 16 (Box 1)
    - 1907 August 21 (Box 1)
    - 1907 September 11 (Box 1)
    - 1907 September 20 (Box 1)
    - 1907 September 26 (Box 1)
    - 1907 October 10 (Box 1)
    - 1907 October 16 (Box 1)
    - 1907 December 6 (Box 1)
    - 1907 December 14 (Box 1)
    - 1908 January 27 (Box 1)
    - 1908 February 20 (Box 1)
    - 1908 March 9 (Box 1)
    - 1908 May 16 (Box 1)
    - 1910 February 5 (Box 1)
    - 1911 July 31 (Box 1)
    - 1911 August 3 (Box 1)
    - 1911 August 9 (Box 1)
    - 1911 November 6 (Box 1)
    - 1911 November 11 (Box 1)
    - 1911 December 11 (Box 1)
    - 1912 January 1 (Box 1)
    - 1912 February 10 (Box 1)
    - 1912 May 1 (Box 1)
    - 1912 November 17 (Box 1)
    - 1922 February 5 (Box 1)
    - 1923 May 5 (Box 1)
  - Frank, Waldo, undated, (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - Gilder, Richard Watson
    - 1902 January 3 (Box 1)
    - 1906 January 15 (Box 1)
    - 1906 January 27 (Box 1)
    - 1906 February 5 (Box 1)
    - 1906 February 9 (Box 1)
    - 1906 February 24 (Box 1)
    - 1906 May 15 (Box 1)
    - 1906 May 25 (Box 1)
    - 1907 February 8 (Box 1)
    - 1907 March 19 (Box 1)
    - 1907 June 2 (Box 1)
    - 1908 March 20 (Box 1)
  - Glaspell, Susan, undated (Box 1)
  - Goldman, Emma, 1913 December 18 (Box 1)
  - Henry (?), 1935 September 18 (Box 1)
  - Johnston, Mary 1928 October (Box 1)
  - Kenton, Edna
    - Gilder, Richard Watson, 1906 undated (Box 1)
    - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1908 April 7 (Box 1)
    - Clark, Mr., 1921 May 12 (Box 1)
    - E.C.M., 1904 August 13 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Delia and Nathaniel Hawthorne, undated (Box 1)
    - Glaspell, Susan, 1924 October 28-November 3 (Box 1)
    - Schedule of Contributions to Magazines, 1902-1906 (Box 1)
    - Henry (?), 1936 January 10 (Box 1)
    - Steru, Frieda, 1935, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1936 March 25 (Box 1)
  - M., E.C.
    - 1904 January 14 (Box 1)
    - 1904 July 25 (Box 1)
    - 1904 August 11 (Box 1)
    - 1904 August 22 (Box 1)
    - 1904 December 7 (Box 1)
    - 1904 December 17 (Box 1)
    - 1905 March 1 (Box 1)
  - Matthews, Brander, 1920 September 15 (Box 1)
  - Mencken, Henry Louis
    - undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1916 April 12 (Box 1)
    - 1917 February 6 (Box 1)
  - Nathan, George Jean, 1918 September 3 (Box 1)
  - O'Neill, Eugene Gladstone, 1924 June 2 (Box 1)
  - Oppenheim, James
    - 1911 November 20 (Box 1)
    - 1916 June 17 (Box 1)
  - Reber, Mabel Kenton, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Sandburg, Carl, undated (Box 1)
  - Sokei-an Sasaki-san, 1930-1937 (Box 1)
  - Spingarn, Joel E., 1920 August 10 (Box 1)
  - Splint, F. W.
    - 1908 December 8 (Box 1)
    - 1908 December 14 (Box 1)
    - 1908 December 22 (Box 1)
    - 1909 January 30 (Box 1)
  - Steru, Frieda, 1935-1937 (Box 1)
  - Towne, Charles Hanson
    - 1903 (Box 1)
    - 1903 September 25 (Box 1)
    - 1905 January 4 (Box 1)
    - 1905 April 5 (Box 1)
    - 1905 April 20 (Box 1)
    - 1905 May 15 (Box 1)
    - 1905 June 9 (Box 1)
    - 1905 July 21 (Box 1)
    - 1905 August 26 (Box 1)
    - 1905 September 11 (Box 1)
    - 1905 September 25 (Box 1)
    - 1905 October 19 (Box 1)
    - 1905 November 3 (Box 1)
    - 1905 November 28 (Box 1)
    - 1905 December 19 (Box 1)
    - 1906 January 15 (Box 1)
    - 1906 March 19 (Box 1)
    - 1906 March 23 (Box 1)
    - 1906 May 1 (Box 1)
    - 1906 May 10 (Box 1)
    - 1906 June 4 (Box 1)
    - 1906 June 8 (Box 1)
    - 1906 June 21, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1906 June 26 (Box 1)
    - 1906 July 9 (Box 1)
    - 1906 July 17 (Box 1)
    - 1906 August 2 (Box 1)
    - 1906 September 7 (Box 1)
    - 1906 September 28 (Box 1)
    - 1906 November 20 (Box 1)
    - 1906 November 28 (Box 1)
    - 1906 December 8 (Box 1)
    - 1906 December 24 (Box 1)
    - 1907 January 4 (Box 1)
    - 1907 January 16 (Box 1)
    - 1907 February 15 (Box 1)
    - 1907 March 2 (Box 1)
    - 1907 May 2 (Box 1)
    - 1907 August 28 (Box 1)
    - 1907 September 12 (Box 1)
    - 1907 October 16 (Box 1)
    - 1907 November 14 (Box 1)
    - 1908 January 2 (Box 1)
    - 1908 January 15 (Box 1)
    - 1908 April 6 (Box 1)
    - 1908 April 15 (Box 1)
    - 1909 April 25 (Box 1)
  - Van Vechten, Carl
    - undated, (7 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1915, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1915 November 11 (Box 1)
    - 1916 January 15 (Box 1)
    - 1916 November 28 (Box 1)
    - 1917 (Box 1)
    - 1935 December 21 (Box 1)
  - Yard, Robert Sterling, 1913 August -October (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1920-1948 (Box 1)
  - Catalog of Incunabula, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The Century--The Militant Women-and Women by Edna Kenton, 1913 November (Box 1)
  - Drawing (unsigned), undated (Box 1)
  - Kenton, Simon--Clippings, Photostat, Negatives, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - Postcards (blank), undated (Box 1)
  - Postcards (various), 1929 1932, undated (Box 1)
  - Printed Matter and Clippings, 1900-1948 (Box 1)
  - The Prodigal Daughter: A Comedy in One Act by F. Sheehy Skeffington--Pamphlet, 1915 June (Box 1)
  - The Provincetown Players--Productions of, 1915-1922 (Box 1)